Guide to the György Kepes papers M1796
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3: Books
  - 3.3. Light Book photographs [as labeled]
    - Architecture (Box 71, Folder 1)
      11 photographs: Midtown Manhatten early evening, Baton Rouge Refinery late evening, building with numbered doors, a mosque or temple, 2 photos of Amsterdam, Ramaswarma Mosque, "La Cisterne Portugaise",3 photos of buildings on the Island of Hydras.
    - Architecture (Box 71, Folder 8)
      22 photographs: University Church entrance (Frank Lloyd Wright design), St. John's Abbey Church, Katsura Palace- taken Yasohiro Ishimoto, photo of "Habitat 67", S.C. Johnson wax factory inside (Frank Wright design), Entrance to building, Nigastu Temple, church window in St. Remy de Baccarat, interior of Ronchamp Chapel, U.S Air Force Academy, buildings in Brussles, 11 undescribed photos.
    - Architecture (Box 72, Folders 1-2)
      22 photographs: 8 images of "Mobility Patterns", La Vaille Cybernetique booklet by Nicolas Schoffer, Tour Lumiere Cybernatique (Paris), Stockholm at night, P.L. Nervi- Palazzo Esposizione Turin (x2), McGregor Memorial Community Conference Center (Michigan), postcard of Palazzo di Teodorico dall'areo, photo of the National Center for Atmospheric Research, Eduard Durell Stone's design of a Musical Water Tower, Water Tank on Neville Island, 2 images of Rameswarma Mosque, View of Rockefellar Plaza with the R.C.A building in the center, a house in Arpajon France; 21 photographs: 2 photos of Berlin at night, Esso Standard Oil Refinery loading racks, Refinery in Baltimore Maryland, View toward Brooklyn from the Brooklyn Bridge, picture of Air Blast Serface breaker by General Electric, French Embassy 1951- photo by Belin, 2 different renderings of Ville Cybernetique, Blue Mosque - Istanbul, Towers of Automex, Blanpain Massonet- Brussels, Drug Store Window Display- South Boston, Interior of Church, 7 pictures of interiors and exteriors of building.
    - Architecture (Box 73, Folder 2)
      22 photographs: Annunciation Priory- Bismark North Dakota, Washington Monument in the heavy fog, Chemical Product Division in Baton Rouge, photo by Yoshio Wantanabe, interior of Caracas University(x2), Interior of Hagia Sophia, interior of Johnson & Johnson Factory, 10 photos by Masayuki Nagare, 4 undescribed photos.
    - Architecture (Box 74, Folder 8)
      17 photographs: 2 photos of windows reflecting light, 10 photos of the "Towers of Automex", Rautatalo Helsingissa, Ispahan- interior of mosque, Katzura- photo by Ito, Granada Alhambra- Padiglione del Patio dei Leoni, wall division utilizing light and shadow patterns.
    - Architecture (Box 77, Folder 2)
      19 Photographs: Torino- Carignano (piazza), Amsterdam warehouse, Milano Palazzo, a tower at Satellite City, Ispahan Mosque, Stainless Steel screen, Marcel Brewer- Sarah Lawrence Academy, 2 photos of Refineries in Texas and Louisiana, Cityscape of New york, photos of inside the Guggenheim, St. Johnson Abbey Church, New York City Buildings, photo of front of building (no description), 5 undescribed photos.
    - Architecture- Exterior and Interior (Box 76, Folder 3)
      11 photographs: wall, doorway by Phota Ito, A church in Boston, Katzura photos by Watanabe and Ito, Annecy France- The Old Quarter, photo by Mies Van Der Roche, Front entrance of Corning Glass Center, Johnson Wax company (by Frank Lloyd Wright), "Iron House" Office Building, 2 undescribed photos.
    - Architecture/ Light Displays (Box 72, Folder 7)
      25 photographs: Palazzo della sport- Luigi Nervi, 4 photos of NY buildings at night, Wrigley Building- Chicago, Roman Forum at night, Van Nelle Factory at night, 2 photos of Gossau Plant, Moving Neon Lighting at Milan Fair (1958), Lucio Fontana- Concetto Spaziale, Libbey Owens- Ford Glass Company, Light Sculpture Photos by Nishan Bichajian, 6 undescribed photos of light displays, 5 undescribed photos of architecture.
    - Art on Canvas (Box 69, Folder 3)
      16 Photographs: Korin- Two Fold Landscape Screen, Georges De La Tour- The Education of the Virgin, Lucio Fontano- Concetto, Robert Motherwell- Granada, Georges Suerat- House and Place De La Concorde (Winter), Turner- North Coast of Whales, Lyonel Feininger- Dunes With Ray of Light, 2 postcards St. Peters Basillica, Firenze Galleria Degli Uffizi "Notti", Giorgione- The Tempest, The Prison (Etching), 4 undescribed.
    - Art using Mixed Mediums (Box 68, Folders 10-12)
      7 photographs: Bartolomeo Schedoni- La Deposizione, Rembrandt- The Three Crosses "drypoint etching", The Slave Ship- by J.M.W. Turner, Pieta- by Michelangelo, St. Peter in Chains- Michelangelo, Pottery Tray (Japanese), Disc with flange around center hole (China), 2 undescribed photographs; 30 photographs of sculptures: Mathias Goeritz- "The Overhanging House", The Towers of Automex, Sam Markle- "still life" neon sculpture, Kopf einer Monumental statue at Athens, Jean Arp- Concrete a la coupe verticale, Mace Head from Tel Agrab (mesopotamia), undescribed photo of stone tablets in the ground, Photo of a Bamboo sculpture, 5 photo booklet of "Continuous Tension Surfaces", "Epoxy over plaster core" by Norman Carlberg, 6 page booklet of concrete sculptures and mortar deformed surfaces, Moon Marker s- by lila Kastzen, Untitled 1965 sculpture by david von Schlegell, Jaques Lipchitz - Song of the Vowels, Sophie Taeuber-Arp- "Releif Rond en Trois Lanteurs", Jean Arp - Concrete Sculpture, Vera Simmons- Aerial Sculpture booklet, 5 undescribed sculptures; 34 photos of Artwork using Artificial Light: Lila Katzen- "Stuffed Lights" and "Moon-Marker", Photo of Dried Palm Leaf, 4 photos of "Fluid Mech", 4 photos of Roger Vilder's " Pulsation" and 2 photos of "Contraction", Colin Greenly - JVD, Gary Rieveschl 4 photo's,Wen-Ying Tsai- " Cybernetic Environment", 11 undescribed.
    - Art using Mixed Mediums (Box 69, Folder 8, Box 70, Folder 1)
      31 photographs: sculptures "Essence" and "Noh play" by Masayuki Nagare, 3 photos "Rythmus im raum" by Max Bill (Zurich), Theodore Brown- "Mobile light Statue", 2 photos Stan Vanderbeeks "Found Forms" film performance, Squares on Wall by Russell, Freeway Reflector Wall, Wire Mobile (M.I.T Design Course), 2 photos of light sculptures, flashlight in dark by D. monell, sculpture by Bronowski, optical texture created by shadows on a surface articulated by dowels, 15 undescribed photos; 8 photographs: Ceramics by A. Maurgiarottie, Discs illuminated by light, projected light on a surface, pliant plastic models, Shadowed dowels illuminated by light, Advanced Visual Study by Kepes, Bending Metal by John P. Shaw, picture of fractal.
    - Art using Mixed Mediums (Box 71, Folder 2)
      19 Photographs: North Bennet St. Playground- Boston, 2 undescribed photos of interior design, painting of an interior room- Amsterdamn, Japanese interior art, undescribed photo of a collage of photos on a wall, Alain Jaquet- Cast iron with brail, Classical era pottery, iron crosses imprinted on wall, 3 undesrcibed photos, indigenous pictoral writings, Rembrandt the philisophes, Alfred Stieglitz-Paula, Portriat of Filippo Archinto- Titian, Jean Otth printed article, Poster for Jean Otth exhibit, M.I.T Art Newspaper (4 pages).
    - Artificial Light (Box 68, Folder 8)
      6 photos of light through tempered glass.
    - Artifical Light (Box 71, Folders 4-5)
      15 Photographs: Otto Piene manuscript describing 7 slides given to G. Kepes, Rockne Krebs- Ra design drawing, Trickfotographie un grafik with Description, Otto Pienne- Light Ballet, Chalermpol Intha- photographer was Nishan Bichajian, Tension picture "1960/63", Man Ray- Rayograph 1922, Man Ray- Woman (Solarized Negative), Espaces Spheriques, Brise-Lumiere au Salon des Realities Nouvelles (1964), Sculpturos Temperelle en action (1959), photo labled "Palatnik", Gabrielle Devecchi- Superfice in Vibrazione, Martha Boto- Chromocinetique, Vardanega- Lucioles Electroniques, Cubed Light display in Moscow, Russia; 25 Photographs: 2 photos of electronic abstractions, Michael Gelick- Glow bar (Sketch), Light Fixture designed by Masayuki Nagare, 5 photos of Pulsa Installation at Yale Golf Course (1969), 2 pictures of "Innertube" by John Reilly-Rudi Stern, 2 photos by Filipo Panseca- "Enviorment Fluids Traveling" and "luminous modular element through clear block, Light projection onto surface, 3 pictures "sand lacking"?, Julio Le Parc- "virtual images placement du spectacular" and "continual mobile", 2 photos by Len Lye- Fountain, Rockne Krebs- Stern Line, Bruno Munari- Lampada Tubolare,Alberto Burri- Ferro, Instabilite- Julio Le Parc, undescribed photo of light design.
    - Artificial Light Displays (Box 72, Folder 3)
      19 photoraphs: Martial Raysse- High Tension painting, Willenbecher- Silver and White, Martial Raysse- Printemps, 4 photos by julio Le Parc, high speed photos of Dynamite Caps (x2), Otto Pienne- Milky Way, 2 photos by Otto Pienne- Onion Flower, projected light reflections - Scene from a Light Ballet, G. Kepes- Light Texture (1940), Electric Discharge Figure- A. von Hippel, George Sugasawara- L.A Lightscape, Gyula Kosice- Traite Poetique, 2 undescribed photos.
    - Artificial Light Displays (Box 73, Folder 4)
      34 Photographs: Tower of Light- Charles Center, Ugo Lapietra- Audio Visual Enviorments, Hein Gravenhorse- "Rotation", Magnetic field about a ferromagnetic recording wire, Picture of prism, Herb Gessner- motorized plexiglass, Light Structure- Kepes student work, 27 undescribed photos.
    - Computer/Light Display (Box 72, Folder 4)
      13 photographs: 6 Computer graphics by John Whitney, Light Sculpture- Michio Ihara, E-motion picture- Nr. 2, Micrograph of a platinum crystal magnified- Erwin Muller (x2 different Magnification), Prisme- Studio Yves Hervochoa, 1 photo by Julio Le Parc, Mirrored Room by Lucas Samaras, Photo of Exhibition structure designed by Will Burtin (1960).
    - Environmental forms (Box 15, Folders 2-3)
      Photographs by Ugo Mulas, Carlotta Carpron, Lotte Jacobi. Photographs of works by John Willenbecher, Gunther Uecker, Lucio Fontana, Dan Flavin, Giacomo Balla, Moholy-Nagy, Seurat, and from Standard Oil Company and MIT student work, Lila Katzen, Wen-Ying Tsai, Matt Glavin and Donald Campbell, many unlabeled.
    - Form Modeling (Box 76, Folder 1)
      23 Photographs: 2 of "Installation" by Gerold Lang, Wooden Sculpture photo by Masayuki Nagare, Slide- Gerald Lang, Hazardous Encounter- Hubert Faber, programmed walls- G. Kepes, 16 undescribed photos, Plain Carbon Steel Isothermally Transformed.
    - Form Modeling/Light Displays (Box 76, Folder 2)
      7 photos of Olympic Rainbow in Munich, Light display in Times Square, Small Orrery by Benjamin Martin, photo by Niguchi, Fibrila form, Beef Tendon, Plain Carbon Steel Isothermally Transformed, 3 undescribed photos.
    - Landscapes (Box 68, Folder 3)
      9 photographs of natural enviorment: photo of 200 acres of strip cropping, "100-inch" Copernicus moon photo, 2 photos Amianta Collosa Conrad, photo of fractal, Photo of Water, photo of Moon Craters, "Flights over Ancient Cities of Iran" site of Abu Nasr near Shiraz, Wantanabe- Pictor (Katzura).
    - Landscapes (Box 70, Folder 5)
      10 photographs: Michigan- contour and straight strips, Minnasota - Contour Strip Cropping (x2), Wisconsin- contoured strip cropping, Pennsylvania strip cropping, Iowa Strip Cropping, Aerial view Arizona, 4 undescribed aerial views of towns by a river.
    - Light Book (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Light Book Slides and Negatives (Box 84, Box 85, Folder 1)
      335 in all.
    - Light Book, 76 photographs by G. Kepes (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Microbiology (Box 69, Folder 1)
      10 photographs: Diffraction pattern, Tobacco mosaic virus (shadowed with nickel), Electric discharge pattern, correspondence from A.S. El-Ani to professor Gyorgy Kepes, photograph of electron micrograph, photo of Bryozoan Membranipora on the Alga Macrocystic, 2 photos of crystals of virus, photo of six foot model of the interior of a human cell, Vitamin A- micrograph, electron micrograph of Myogoblin, 3 undescribed photos of a cell.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 9)
      22 photographs: Sketch of a cityscape, Giorgio de Chirco- The Delights of the Poet, correspondance from G. Kepes to Adolf Buchleiter/Roman Verostko, Pierre Cordier pamphlet, 3 images from the Atlas Rocket- Puerto Rico, Central Sahara, Lake Rudolf, Houdon Sculpture- Voltaire/Moliere/Jean Jaques Rousseau/Diderot, "Model of 8 Surprises", image of New England, 2 images of Morrocco, 7 undescribed photos.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 71, Folders 6-7)
      18 photographs: 2 photos of Isamu Naguchi, 4 balls lined up horizontally illuminated- photo by Nishan Bichajian, Etienne Hajdu- cock, Diamond shaped chairs- Harry Bertoia, 3 photos by Jack Burnham, Design System (DSM) 4 page pamphlet accompanied with 4 DSM photos, "flying turtle" and "the princess" sculpture by Constatin Branuschi, Felip Panesca- living heated sphere (x2), 1 undescribed photo; 24 Photographs: 13 images of Circle patterns, Glass lamp of Kartin Al-Din (12 century Syria), undescribed photo -"1955" on back, Beryl Sokoloff sculpture, Paytones- James Gentry, Elephant ear picture taken with sun behind it, patterns made by crabs in the sand, picture of fountain, 2 photos of water reflecting light, Garden from Katzura palace - Watanabe, Church Tower shortly after erecting without bells.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 1)
      23 photographs: Tete de Christ- Strasbourg, Library at Caracas University, 19 photos of Continuous Membranes by Erwin Hauer, 3 undescribed photos.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 6)
      19 photographs: photo of Jade axe head and knife, Chicken display case, Piano solo (written), 4 photos by Julio Le Parc, 12 pictures by Kurasawa from Macbeth/Rashomon/Seven Samurai.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 8)
      26 photographs: Alabaster cylinder vase, 22 undescribed photos, cityscape of Sunnyvale, Boston at Night, le Coursier- Marseille Building.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 74, Folders 4-6)
      10 photos: correspondence to Kepes from Eric sutherland, Design Quarterly 53 from Walker Art Center, photo of a light display, 6 photos with the words "Nanda Vigo" written on the back, 1 undescribed photo; 19 Photographs: 5 photos displaying use of shadows, Otto Pienne- the proliferation of the sun(x2), Otto Pienne- 3 white light ghosts, wheel with heads in position, 2 photos of 2d box with windows, windflower- kraushaar gallery, Harold Tovish- the tenant, Mathia Goertz- Pliage, photo by Julio Le Parc, Yves Klein- Fever Wand, Robert whitman- Pond, Jose De Rivera- Construction 72, Contour model study with two light sources, Head of prince from Giza (limestone); 14 photographs: 7 "physics photos", Earl Reiback- Luminar, continual lumination area by Le Parc, photo labeled "sprouting", 4 undescribed photos.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 75, Folder 7)
      8 photographs: 5 photos of different aerial views, photo of front of house by Watanabe, design for Milan Triennale, parking lot.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 6)
      23 Photos: Courtyard of a Building in Ruins- Canaletto, 20 undescribed photos, correspondence, photos of William Blake sketches.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 1)
      24 photographs: 5 photos by Masayuke Nagare, Mylar Mirror at the Jewish Museum, Karl Gerstner- Lens #15, 2 undescribed sketches,2 photos of hanging round mirrors, opaque white perforated cube under different lights, Fontana, Concetto Espeziale, Pierre Soulages painting, The Doves- Bologna, L'Annunzata Scuola- Venetzia, Photo of Caracas University, Descombin- Outside Sculpture wiht Modular Units, "Marckab" by victor De Vasarely, photos of sculptures at Caracas University, 2 photos of 3rd Century B.C handmade Bowls, 12 undescribed photos.
    - Movie Photography (Box 68, Folder 13)
      8 photos of Charles Chaplin in "City Lights", poster of "Nanda Vigo", 2 photos of "The Long Voyage Home", 1 photo of "Grapes of Wrath", 1 undescribed.
    - Outer Space (Box 70, Folder 9)
      9 photos: Hurricane Beulah Sattelite shot, Solar System NGC-527Y, Solar Flares from Sacramento Observatory and Palomar, Solar System NGC-284l, Solar System M31 Andromeda, Mount Wilson and Palomar Observatories- Sygnus, Mount Wilson Observatory -Comet Cunningham, Mount Wilson and Palomar Observatories- Prominence "whole edge of sun taken with calcium" and Solar Corona photographed at total eclipse.
    - Paintings on Canvas (Box 73, Folder 5)
      14 photographs: Jan Vermeer- The Concert, Carravagio- La Madonna della Serpe, Johannes Vermeer- Lady with a Lute, Georges Seurat- Three Women, Carvaggio- Voccazione di San Matteo, Georges de La Tour- Le Fumeur, Carvaggio- Madonna the Serpe, rembrante- Verlorchening Van Petrius, 7 undescribed paintings.
    - Paintings/Drawings on Canvas (Box 74, Folder 7)
      7 photographs: F. M collection from MOMA-NY, Giorgione- La Tempesta, Paolo Veronese- Cena di Gesu in Casa di Levi, El Greco- The Adoration of the Shepards, Ben Nichalson- Green Hand, Adolphe Appia- Rhythmic Space, Rene Magritte- Empire of Light II.
    - Pamphlets and Booklets (Box 73, Folder 7)
      10 photographs: Correspondence between G. Kepes and G. Soava, Arte Programmata, Kosice- New York exhibition, Medardo Rosso- MOMA New York, Church at Las Condes: Architecture at Rice, Uecker- Howard Wise Gallery, Electronic Light Displays by Ben F. Laposky, 10 undescribed photos of light displays, Virtual volume by revolving wire.
    - Photographs (Box 69, Folder 6)
      16 photographs: Claire Legeume Art- 8 pictures, Carro- 1958, Caminos- Portfolio Structure, Hologram of a Wire, Electronic Abstraction- Oscillation #12, "Onion Flower"- Lighting Foyer of The New City Opera House (Bonn), Bruno Mumari- Polariscop (1965), General Line U.S.S.R 1929 (Sergei Eisenstein?), U.S rescue submarine.
    - Photographs (Box 70, Folder 6)
      37 photographs: Cameroon Tribal Boys, Skiiers in Switzerland, desrciption of "projection of a cube", Arrowhead from the Shang period, Mayan design on wall, 2 ladies in a window, 4 verticle shadowed balls, interior of chapel, blanket cave, 6 photos from Toshiyo Yoshida, 2 photos of Walter Vivrett's Motion Study, 3 close-ups of dimpled glass, rotating light reflection, electronic light display in NY, M. Descombin- releif Dynamystique (x2), Modulation sur le Carre- Descombin, Herbert Gasner- plexiglass construction, Moholy-Nagy oil on canvas, "Eggscape", 11 undescribed photos.
    - Photographs (Box 70, Folder 8)
      23 photographs: 20 M.I.T students sculptures photos, Video tape stills (x3),"Chalermpol Intha" 7 photos.
    - Photographs (Box 71, Folder 3)
      6 Photographs: Italian Christmas display, electronic light display, Proton producing 26 charged particles, Vortex- generator fountain, 2 undescribed pictures.
    - Places (Box 69, Folders 4-5)
      20 Photographs: Hugo Garcia Perez- Streets of Jeruselum and Street Scene in Kashmir India, Spring in Boston- 1955, Oakland Bay Bridge by Jeffery Heller 1966, 5 photos of Isfahan Mosque, Palomar Observatory- Comet Cunningham, 2 photos Casa Mila and 1 of Casa Batllo (Barcelona), Bernini Colonade, Niger- Air Agades, "The African Town" Photo, A House Deck by Wantanabe, A Venice Reflection by Kepes; 24 Photographs: Pittsburg "Gas Works" on Ohio River, New York Central Railroad Yards, stove #20 in cattlemans hut at Boston/Albany freight station, "Action Sugar Beet"and "Action Water Piece-Tree" -Germany (1969), Hagi City Hall- Tokyo Japan, Hamburg Cityscape- Germany, Empire State Building (view from atop RCA), 5 Towers of Automex(Mexico), Rome- St. Peters at night, Sudanese Mosque, Model of glass skysrcaper (MOMA, NY), L.A Cityscape from Palomar Observatory, Port Allen-Southern Louisiana, Patio de l'Alberca- Granda, Aerial View of Vermont highway, 8 undescribed.
    - Projected Lights (Box 15, Folders 4-6)
      50 photographs by Bernice Abbot (Educational Services), Pierre Cordier, Ezra Stoller, Standard Oil Company, and Michio Ihara, and of works by Kosice, Otto Piene, Julio Le Parc, Max Bill (with possible signature), Pulsa, Carlos Ortuzar, Otto Piene, Ted Kraynik, Nicolas Schoeffer, Gerald Oster, and from MIT VIsual Design course. Also includes journal tearsheet with image, Norman Carlberg exhibition catalog from 1966 show at Pennsylvania State University and exhibition catalog pamphlet of Shoeffer show at The Institute of Contemporary Arts, London, 1960.
    - Reliefs, Exterior (Box 68, Folder 5)
      5 photographs of tapestry.
    - Reliefs, Interior (Box 68, Folder 7)
      5 photographs of interior design.
    - Science (Box 75, Folders 2-6)
      30 photographs: 13 pictures of sounds captured using light, 4 photos of oscillagraphs, C. Maxwell- Treatise on Electricity and Magnetism, photo of a small explosion, x-ray oscillation, 10 undescribed photos of light oscillations; 19 photos: Electronic Instrumentation photo, a jet of air discharging at high pressure, x-ray of columbine flower, 16 undescribed and unlabeled photos; 14 photos: 7 photos from Harry Holtzman Collection, 5 photos of galaxies, Major Storms capture by a Weather Satellite, 1 undescribed photo of a painting; 39 Photographs: Fluid Mapper by A. D. Moore, Electric Discharge Figure by A. Von Hippel, 3 Electron Micrscope photos of Robber Fly, Domain Pattern on Surface, Silicon Epitaxial Wafer photo by Jack Kath, electric discharge, 3 electron Microscope photos of human hair, Mercury Dimes, tracks of particles from a speck of radium, x-ray of tulips, Electron Microscope of Molybdenum oxide, Asymmetrical contours of single crystal by S. Tolansky, 2 photos of Tobacco Virus by Tolansky, 21 undescribed photos using scientific instruments to capture them; 20 photographs: Electron Micrograph of Human Hair and Robber Fly, "strain Diagrams", Electron Micrgraph by J.A. Kessel, Skelton of a Sea Urchin, 2 photos of insect wing, spiderweb with water drops, photo of Berylium, 2 photos of electric discharge, 20 undescribed photos.
    - Science (Box 76, Folder 5)
      26 photographs: Oscilliscope pattern, Oscilligram, Luminouse Mobile by Robert Mallary (x4), reflections of water in movement, Light patterns projected on photosensitive emulsion, Light Shower- student work, Visual Design Project- Koichi Yokota, 2 photos of x-rays of life forms, 14 undescribed photos.
    - Science (Box 77, Folder 3)
      26 photographs: Spiral Nebula, Gaseous Nebula, 2 aerial sattelite photos, typical hologram, close-up of a robber fly, Carbon Replica of freshly Fractured surface, super strength steel close up, spiral growth on crystal silicone, aerolite, electric discharge, "Hydro-Light"/Horizon of Water/traite of Poetry- Gyula Kosice, Plexiglass figure, 11 undescribed photos.
    - Scientific Art (Box 76, Folder 4)
      44 photographs: 9th Annual Contemporary Art of Japan Exhibit, Bisthmus Telluride, Hollowed out Plexiglass sculpture, Triangulated infinite periodic structural system by Peter Pearce, Wall sculpture at Caracas University, Model for Christian Pavillion 1970 Expo, 2 photos Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam, 2 photos by Micho Ihara, Plexiglass construction, Nicholas Schoffer model, Light Mould- MOMA NY, Tooled Transparent Material, Naum Gobo- Linear Construction, Moholy Nagy- Twisted Planes, Naum Gabo- Contstruction in Space with Balance on Two Points, Colin Greenly Glass sculpture- 2 photos, Light emanating from within a transparent structure, 3 photos of Transparent Sculpture by Louise Nevelson, 3 photos of Charles Ross Sculptures, Cybernetic Sculpture by Tsai, mirrored distortion by Daniel Babitch, 10 undescribed photos.
    - Sculptures (Box 68, Folder 4)
      4 photographs of sculptures: Pre-historic Japanese pottery, outside sculpture by Constantino Nifphilor, sculpture on wall at Yale, outside wall sculpture.
    - Sculptures (Box 69, Folder 2)